designer & entrepreneur

SKILLS

Sketch

Illustrator, CC

HTML/CSS

Bootstrap 4

JavaScript

Angular 8

Competitive Analysis

User Research

Persona Development

Defining Voice

Journey Maps

Storyboards

Moodboards

Sketching

Mockups

Wireframes User Flows

Site Maps

Prototyping

User Testing

Mobile Design

Desktop Design

Product Management

Lean & Agile

Kanban

Presenting Ideas

Written Communication

Photoshop, CC

Lightroom, CC

DSLR Photography

Print Design

MailChimp Campaigns

Mac & PC

PROFILE

I am a UX/UI designer with experience taking ideas from design to development. I am incredibly motivated by innovative collaboration, the freedom to invent and brainstorm, and by passionate people who think outside the box. I have experience working on a team of UX and UI designers, and with software engineers, product teams, and business owners. I have experience working in an iterative Agile/Lean environment where I spend time doing competitive analyses, user research, brand development, creating designs, user testing, presenting ideas, and refining ideas.

I am also an entrepreneur, photographer, and product developer. I have an entrepreneurial mindset and love to wear multiple hats. I strive to do meaningful work, above all else. Whether I'm creating the designs myself, developing vision to match business needs, managing a team, or starting my own business, my goal is to help build a successful company.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance **UX & Website Designer** October 2019 - present

I work on various short-term freelance projects. I'm currently working with a small start-up as their lead UX designer while the business scales. I am in charge of leading design initiatives and brand vision for the product. I have taken ideas to development by doing a competitive analysis, user research, prioritizing features based on business goals, developing brand guidelines, developing personas, and creating mockups. I work directly with the CEO on business needs and strategy, and the software engineer on developing designs.

Guardian Life Insurance Co. / ReedGroup UX|UI Designer

May 2019 - August 2019

I worked on an Agile and Kanban team, attended Agile meetings with engineers, and completed work via User Stories within 10-day Sprints. I did user research to create and refine mockups and to build prototypes for presentation to product owners, account executives and for user testing. I presented work using personas, user flows, and journey maps to tell a story. I assisted in developing user testing scripts, performing user tests, compiling data, and presenting research findings.

ReedGroup

UI Designer & Front-End Developer April 2018 - May 2019

I learned and began working as an Agile and Kanban team as the company implemented it across the software and technology department. I attended all Agile meetings and ceremonies and completed work via User Stories within 10-day sprints. I refined our internal style guide using Bootstrap, and implemented a new way of defining spacing guidelines to engineers. I did user research to create and refine mockups and to build prototypes for presentation to product owners, account executives and for user testing. I presented work using personas, user flows, and journey maps to tell a story. I assisted in developing user testing scripts, performing user tests, compiling data, and presenting research findings.

The Rolland Group Visual Designer July 2016 - March 2018

I helped implement design into this small startup company. I revised existing print graphics to meet current design standards. I designed email campaigns via MailChimp and HTML. I designed web-based and print graphics. I worked directly with the marketing team to create content for advertising that would work well with email and graphic designs.

EDUCATION

Indiana University, Bloomington

Bachelor of Science, Kinesiology Major: Exercise Science; Minor: Psychology

Additional Learning:

User Experience Design

Entrepreneurship

Psychology

Agile/Lean/Kanban

DSLR Photography

Product Management

Training:

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

PORTFOLIO BUSINESS EMAIL PHONE INSTAGRAM

elizabethsasseman.com elizabethsassemandesigns.com elizabethsasseman@gmail.com 317.219.9456 @elizabethsassemandesigns